(typing)
(upbeat music)
All right, welcome back to the next section
where we will now take your CSS skills to the next level.
So up until this point, we have used CSS
to add visual styles and spacing to elements.
However, CSS can be used for much more than just that.
And in fact, one of the main applications
of CSS is to build layouts.
And so that's what we're gonna do next.
So in this section, you will learn
how to build layouts using floats
and also using two really modern technologies,
which are called flexbox and CSS Grid.
And in fact, this is gonna be
one of the most important sections of this course.
And so really make sure to take all the time
that you need to understand it.
That's really important, but anyway,
let's get back to work right away.